eftps.com 2015-03-17

# Welcome To EFTPS - Help and Information

You are using an Official United States Government System, which may be used only for authorized purposes. Unauthorized modification of any information stored on this system may result in criminal prosecution. The Government may monitor and audit the usage of this system, and all persons are hereby notified that the use of this system constitutes consent to such monitoring and auditing. Unauthorized attempts to upload information and/or change information on this web site are strictly prohibited and are subject to prosecution under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and Title 18 U.S.C. Sec. 1001 and 1030.

The Electronic Federal Tax Payment System® (EFTPS) doesn't collect personal information when you visit our Web site unless you choose to provide that information.

Information Collected and Stored Automatically

When you visit the EFTPS® tax payment service Web site, we may store some or all of the following: the Internet address from which you access this site, date and time of your visit, the Internet address of the site from which you reached this site, items clicked on a page, forms or processes you viewed, and the browser and operating system used. This information is not associated with individual users other than as specified below.

This information is used to measure the number of visitors to the various sections of our site and identify system performance or problem areas. We also use this information to help us develop the site, analyze patterns of usage, and to make the site more useful. This information is not used for associating search terms or patterns of site navigation with individual users. We may share this information, without revealing your personal information, with third-party entities with whom we contract for the purposes of research analysis.

We also monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise cause damage to the Web site. We focus on Web site security so that this service remains available to you and other visitors. We may use this network traffic information to identify you if we suspect unauthorized or illegal behavior.

In addition, when you use this Web site to enroll in EFTPS® tax payment service or initiate a payment through this EFTPS® tax payment service, we collect personal information about your identity (including but not limited to your taxpayer identification number) and financial accounts. This information is used to create an enrollment in EFTPS® tax payment service and to process tax payments and related forms. More information regarding this information is found in the Privacy Act and Paperwork Reduction Act notice located here. 

Use of Persistent Cookies

Like many Web sites, this site uses "persistent cookie" technology. A persistent cookie is a small text file that this site places on your computer so that it can remember you when you show up again later. Office of Management and Budget guidance classifies these cookies as a Tier 2 Web customization and measurement technology.

We use persistent cookies in two ways, both of which enhance your experience while also protecting your privacy:

  * **To remember you when you come back to the site so we don't invite you to take our customer satisfaction survey every time you visit.** Our customer satisfaction survey uses a persistent cookie to ensure we won't invite you to take another survey within 30 days of having completed one.
  * **To get aggregate metrics on site usage to understand how people are using the site and how we can make it better.** We use Web metrics services to track activity on this site. Government agencies only ever receive traffic statistics anonymously and in the aggregate.

Most Internet browsers automatically accept persistent cookies. EFTPS.gov and EFTPS.com have persistent cookies enabled by default, so that we can gather information that will allow us to improve our service. These cookies are provided by ForeSee Results, Inc. and Google Inc. but are delivered by EFTPS®.

Although we think using persistent cookies creates a much better experience for you, this site will also work without them. If you don't want to accept cookies, you can edit your browser's options to stop accepting persistent cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the Websites you visit. To learn about how to do this, visit: http://www.usa.gov/optout_instructions.shtml. 

Site Security

For site security purposes and to ensure that this tax payment service remains available to all users, we use commercial software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage.

Except for authorized law enforcement investigations, no other attempts are made to identify individual users or their usage habits at this site. Raw data logs are scheduled for regular destruction in accordance with National Archives and Records Administration guidelines. Unauthorized attempts to upload information or change information on this service are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and the National Information Infrastructure Protection Act.

Back to Top

External Links

This site links to a handful of other federal and state government, small business, and tax-related Web sites. If you click a link to a site, you will leave EFTPS.gov or EFTPS.com, and are subject to the privacy and security policies of the owners/sponsors of the outside site.

The Financial Management Service (FMS) and EFTPS.gov/EFTPS.com **do not** control or guarantee the accuracy, relevance, timeliness, or completeness of information contained on a linked site. 

FMS and EFTPS.gov/EFTPS.com **do not** endorse the organizations sponsoring linked sites and we **do not** endorse the views they express or the products/services they offer. 

FMS and EFTPS.gov/EFTPS.com **cannot** authorize the use of copyrighted materials contained in linked sites. Users must request such authorization from the sponsor of the linked site. 

FMS and EFTPS.gov/EFTPS.com **are not** responsible for transmissions users receive from linked sites. 

FMS and EFTPS.gov/EFTPS.com **do not** guarantee that outside sites comply with Section 508 (accessibility requirements) of the Rehabilitation Act. 

EFTPS® will not link to any site that exhibits hate, bias, or discrimination. EFTPS® reserves the right to deny or remove any link that contains misleading information or unsubstantiated claims, or is determined to be in conflict with EFTPS® 's mission or policies.

Social Media

While the EFTPS® tax payment service manages a presence on Twitter to share government information and engage with the public, we do not collect any Personally Identifiable Information through that site. We also do not use personal information made available by the user to that third-party site.

When we update this policy, we will post the new version on this site and include the date of revision. Please review this page periodically.

Version 2.0 (11/15/2012)
